<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>The Gospel</title>
 <link href="http://gospelinsix.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://gospelinsix.com/"/>
 <updated>2017-04-16T21:34:12-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://gospelinsix.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Cross City Church</name>
   <email>scott@crosscitychurch.org</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The Gospel</title>
   <link href="http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/03/the-gospel/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/03/the-gospel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thank you for taking a few moments to consider the message of the Bible, which it calls “The gospel”. The gospel means “Good News”, but its message is actually some very bad news followed by much better news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;audience&quot; href=&quot;#uncertain&quot;&gt;Uncertain about the gospel?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;audience&quot; href=&quot;#skeptical&quot;&gt;Skeptical about the gospel?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;audience&quot; href=&quot;#accept&quot;&gt;Do you accept the gospel?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;snapshot&quot;&gt;The Gospel in a Snapshot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;svg id=&quot;Layer_1&quot; data-name=&quot;Layer 1&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 81.91 73.91&quot;&gt;&lt;defs&gt;&lt;style&gt;.cls-1{fill:#333;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/defs&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;cls-1&quot; d=&quot;M1136,918.16a42.11,42.11,0,0,0-19.53-24.9,26.6,26.6,0,0,0,.24-3.49c0-10.67-6.58-19.91-12.1-25.77a12.46,12.46,0,0,0-18.16,0c-5.52,5.87-12.1,15.1-12.1,25.77a26.56,26.56,0,0,0,.24,3.49,42.11,42.11,0,0,0-19.53,24.9A12.44,12.44,0,0,0,1067.36,934c8.35-.25,19.61-2,28.12-8.64,8.51,6.62,19.77,8.39,28.12,8.64h.39a12.44,12.44,0,0,0,12-15.82Zm-54-28.39c0-8.16,5.45-15.66,10-20.51a4.79,4.79,0,0,1,7,0c4.57,4.85,10,12.35,10,20.51,0,0,0,.07,0,.11a41.73,41.73,0,0,0-27,0S1082,889.81,1082,889.77Zm13.5,23.91c-3.28-2.92-9.21-8.92-12-16.2a34.06,34.06,0,0,1,24,0C1104.68,904.74,1098.75,910.76,1095.48,913.68Zm-28.35,12.62a4.74,4.74,0,0,1-3.92-1.84,4.68,4.68,0,0,1-.82-4.2,34.38,34.38,0,0,1,14.25-19.3c3.5,8.53,10.1,15.22,13.83,18.53C1083.6,924.68,1074.19,926.09,1067.13,926.31Zm60.62-1.84a4.74,4.74,0,0,1-3.92,1.84c-7.06-.21-16.47-1.63-23.34-6.81,3.73-3.31,10.32-10,13.83-18.53a34.38,34.38,0,0,1,14.25,19.3A4.68,4.68,0,0,1,1127.75,924.47Z&quot; transform=&quot;translate(-1054.53 -860.07)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;God&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God made all things for His Glory and communicated with mankind in the Scriptures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;svg id=&quot;Layer_1&quot; data-name=&quot;Layer 1&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 70.42 67.66&quot;&gt;&lt;defs&gt;&lt;style&gt;.cls-1{fill:#333;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/defs&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;cls-1&quot; d=&quot;M1063.16,1033.23a12.36,12.36,0,0,0,9.51,20.27h45.64a12.36,12.36,0,0,0,9.51-20.27,42.07,42.07,0,0,0-15.2-11.49,31.34,31.34,0,0,0,4.05-14.82c0-.33,0-.67,0-1-.51-13.18-11-20.07-21.16-20.07s-20.66,6.89-21.16,20.07q0,.5,0,1a31.34,31.34,0,0,0,4.05,14.82A42.07,42.07,0,0,0,1063.16,1033.23Zm19.46-5a60,60,0,0,0,3.94,4.6,12.28,12.28,0,0,0,17.85,0,59.91,59.91,0,0,0,3.94-4.6,34.4,34.4,0,0,1,13.57,9.9,4.69,4.69,0,0,1-3.62,7.69h-45.64a4.69,4.69,0,0,1-3.62-7.69A34.4,34.4,0,0,1,1082.62,1028.25Zm-.65-21.34c0-.24,0-.47,0-.71.34-8.77,7-12.69,13.5-12.69s13.16,3.92,13.5,12.69q0,.35,0,.7c0,8.22-5.52,15.77-10.15,20.66a4.61,4.61,0,0,1-6.71,0C1087.49,1022.68,1082,1015.13,1082,1006.91Z&quot; transform=&quot;translate(-1060.27 -985.84)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;Man&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All people were created by God for His glory. Mankind was designed to have relationship with God and to have God as the ultimate treasure and authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;svg id=&quot;Layer_1&quot; data-name=&quot;Layer 1&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 72.99 76.92&quot;&gt;&lt;defs&gt;&lt;style&gt;.cls-1{fill:#333;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/defs&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;cls-1&quot; d=&quot;M1095.48,1103.29c-10.13,0-20.66,6.89-21.16,20.07q0,.5,0,1c0,10.75,6.67,20,12.26,25.93a12.28,12.28,0,0,0,17.85,0c5.59-5.9,12.26-15.19,12.26-25.93,0-.33,0-.67,0-1C1116.14,1110.19,1105.62,1103.29,1095.48,1103.29Zm-3.36,41.73c-4.63-4.89-10.15-12.44-10.15-20.66,0-.24,0-.47,0-.71.34-8.77,7-12.69,13.5-12.69s13.16,3.92,13.5,12.69q0,.35,0,.7c0,8.22-5.52,15.77-10.15,20.66a4.61,4.61,0,0,1-6.71,0Z&quot; transform=&quot;translate(-1058.99 -1103.29)&quot; /&gt;&lt;polygon class=&quot;cls-1&quot; points=&quot;70.31 43.42 36.5 56.08 2.69 43.42 0 50.61 25.55 60.17 0 69.74 2.69 76.92 36.5 64.27 70.31 76.92 72.99 69.74 47.44 60.17 72.99 50.61 70.31 43.42&quot; /&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;Fall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But every person has rejected God’s authority and has chosen to be self centered and self directed and thus, commit sinful acts. As a result all people are separated from God, justly sentenced to eternal destruction in Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;svg id=&quot;Layer_1&quot; data-name=&quot;Layer 1&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 63.37 91.92&quot;&gt;&lt;defs&gt;&lt;style&gt;.cls-1{fill:#333;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/defs&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;cls-1&quot; d=&quot;M1095.48,1236l-16,20.6L1063.8,1241v40.95h21.85c-5.27,5.8-11.35,14.71-11.35,25q0,.5,0,1c.51,13.18,11,20.07,21.16,20.07s20.66-6.89,21.16-20.07q0-.5,0-1c0-10.25-6.08-19.16-11.35-25h21.85V1241l-15.66,15.66Zm0,12.5,10.56,13.57-10.56,10.56-10.56-10.56Zm15.3,19.68,4.7,6h-10.74Zm-1.79,38.68c0,.24,0,.47,0,.71-.34,8.77-7,12.69-13.5,12.69s-13.16-3.92-13.5-12.69q0-.35,0-.7c0-10.34,8.76-19.6,13.23-23.65l.28.28.28-.28C1100.24,1287.25,1109,1296.48,1109,1306.87Zm-22.77-32.64h-10.74l4.7-6Zm-11.51-11.51-3.24,4.17v-7.41Zm44.78-3.24v7.41l-3.24-4.17Z&quot; transform=&quot;translate(-1063.8 -1236.01)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;Offer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet God offers the hope of salvation. He gives them the opportunity to end their rebellion… to have God as their rightful authority and treasure. Since that relationship with God would be reconciled, the person would live eternally with God in Heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;svg id=&quot;Layer_1&quot; data-name=&quot;Layer 1&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 42.36 80.39&quot;&gt;&lt;defs&gt;&lt;style&gt;.cls-1{fill:#333;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/defs&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;cls-1&quot; d=&quot;M1074.3,1429.38q0,.5,0,1c.51,13.18,11,20.07,21.16,20.07s20.66-6.89,21.16-20.07q0-.5,0-1c0-14.1-11.5-25.67-16.56-30.08h15.84v-7.67h-16.62v-21.57h-7.67v21.57H1075v7.67h15.84C1085.8,1403.71,1074.3,1415.28,1074.3,1429.38Zm34.68.71c-.27,7-4.61,10.93-9.66,12.21v-33.07c4.44,4.79,9.67,12.13,9.67,20.15C1109,1429.62,1109,1429.85,1109,1430.09Zm-17.33,12.21c-5-1.28-9.39-5.19-9.66-12.21q0-.35,0-.7c0-8,5.23-15.33,9.67-20.13Z&quot; transform=&quot;translate(-1074.3 -1370.06)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;Jesus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to give people this reconciliation, a payment was made. Jesus, being God and man, came to earth in order to live, die and rise from the dead. By doing this, all who would trust in Him would find complete forgiveness for rebellion and would be given Jesus’ righteousness. When Jesus’ work is applied to a person, they are no longer separated from God and actually become His Child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;svg id=&quot;Layer_1&quot; data-name=&quot;Layer 1&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 48.85 74.29&quot;&gt;&lt;defs&gt;&lt;style&gt;.cls-1{fill:#333;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/defs&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;cls-1&quot; d=&quot;M1114.48,1492.68l-19,19-19-19-5.43,5.43,18.7,18.7c-5.46,5-15.46,15.95-15.46,29.09q0,.5,0,1c.51,13.18,11,20.07,21.16,20.07s20.66-6.89,21.16-20.07q0-.5,0-1c0-13.15-10-24.1-15.46-29.09l18.7-18.7Zm-5.49,53.22c0,.24,0,.47,0,.71-.34,8.77-7,12.69-13.5,12.69s-13.16-3.92-13.5-12.69q0-.35,0-.7c0-10.56,9.13-20,13.51-23.91C1099.87,1525.9,1109,1535.31,1109,1545.91Z&quot; transform=&quot;translate(-1071.06 -1492.68)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;Response&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way a person will be reconciled to God through Christ, is by asking God to apply the work of Jesus to transform him from a self- centered rebel, to a God-centered person who loves and obeys Him. Such a repentance and plea for salvation is called “being saved by grace through faith”. From that moment on, God reconciles that person to Himself and He becomes their treasure and authority.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Gospel in Detail</title>
   <link href="http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/02/the-gospel-in-detail/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/02/the-gospel-in-detail</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;god&quot;&gt;God&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God is the only God and is uncreated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Isaiah 43:10-11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Me there was no God formed, And there will be none after Me. I, even I, am the LORD, And there is no savior besides Me.
In the beginning God created everything&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Genesis 1:1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning God created the heavens and the earth.
God’s ultimate motivation is always to show His Glory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Isaiah 48:9,11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sake of My name I delay My wrath, And for My praise I restrain it for you, In order not to cut you off. For My own sake, for My own sake, I will act; for how can My name be profaned? And My glory I will not give to another.
Another way of explaining God’s glory is showing His greatness. God chose to communicate to His creation in two ways. First He showed His power, order and beauty through nature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Romans 1:19-20&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because that which is known about God is evident within them; for God made it evident to them. For since the creation of the world His invisible attributes, His eternal power and divine nature, have been clearly seen, being understood through what has been made, so that they are without excuse.
But He chose to communicate His mercy, values and plan by giving the Scriptures to the world as His authoritative and final Word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2 Peter 1:20-21&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But know this first of all, that no prophecy of Scripture is a matter of one’s own interpretation, for no prophecy was ever made by an act of human will, but men moved by the Holy Spirit spoke from God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;man&quot;&gt;Man&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every person was created for God’s Glory… to be “God-Centered”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Isaiah 43:7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone who is called by My name, And whom I have created for My glory, Whom I have formed, even whom I have made.”
Deuteronomy 6:14-15
“You shall not follow other gods, any of the gods of the peoples who surround you, for the LORD your God in the midst of you is a jealous God; otherwise the anger of the LORD your God will be kindled against you, and He will wipe you off the face of the earth.
Mankind is unique from the rest of creation because he was created with the ability to have relationship with God
Genesis 1:27
God created man in His own image, in the image of God He created him; male and female He created them.
Fall
Every person has rejected God and is not “God- Centered”
Romans 3:23
For all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God.
In doing this, every person has sinned. Sin is rebellion against God’s glory. It is being “self-centered” instead of being “God-centered”. Because this is true, people do sinful actions.
Mark 7:21-22
“For from within, out of the heart of men, proceed the evil thoughts, fornications, thefts, murders, adulteries, deeds of coveting and wickedness, as well as deceit, sensuality, envy, slander, pride and foolishness.
Everyone is spiritually dead, unable to help themselves
Ephesians 2:4-5
But God, being rich in mercy, because of His great love with which He loved us, even when we were dead in our transgressions, made us alive together with Christ (by grace you have been saved).
All people are described as having become enemies of God, therefore the wrath of God is on them and all are facing the just punishment of eternal death.
Colossians 1:21
And although you were formerly alienated and hostile in mind, engaged in evil deeds,…
Romans 6:23
For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.
John 3:36
[…] But he who does not obey the Son will not see life, but the wrath of God abides on him.
Offer
Yet God offers the opportunity to walk away from the self-centered and godless life. This is called repentance.
Acts 26:20
…but kept declaring both to those of Damascus first, and also at Jerusalem and then throughout all the region of Judea, and even to the Gentiles, that they should repent and turn to God, performing deeds appropriate to repentance.
Romans 5:1
Therefore, having been justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ,
God’s kind offer is the chance to be restored in relationship with Him, to be made “God- centered”.
John 17:3
This is eternal life, that they may know You, the only true God, and Jesus Christ whom You have sent.
It is a chance to be owned and ruled by God as the King, completely used for His glory.
1 Corinthians 6:19b-20
…and that you are not your own? For you have been bought with a price: therefore glorify God in your body.
A “God –centered” person not only finds God to be King, but also their greatest treasure.
Deuteronomy 6:5
“You shall love the LORD your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your might.
Psalm 73:25
Whom have I in heaven but You? And besides You, I desire nothing on earth.
This restored relationship lasts forever, even after death, in heaven.
John 10:28
…and I give eternal life to them, and they will never perish; and no one will snatch them out of My hand.
The offer of salvation that God extends is a change of authority: Self will no longer get to be the god. Now, God will be the person’s God. He gets to call the shots and His desires are the most important.
Mark 8:34
And He summoned the crowd with His disciples, and said to them, “If anyone wishes to come after Me, he must deny himself, and take up his cross and follow Me.”
Jesus
God determined that there is only one way in which He would give this offer to save people
John 14:6
Jesus said to him, “I am the way, and the truth, and the life; no one comes to the Father but through Me.
Jesus always was God, and then became a man as well when He came to the earth.
John 1:1
In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God.
He came to earth because each person’s sin must be justly punished. As the perfectly just Judge, He cannot ignore sin.
Romans 2:16
On the day when, according to my gospel, God will judge the secrets of men through Christ Jesus.
By Jesus’ sinless life, death on the cross and resurrection, He took the punishment for sin for all who would trust in Him. In doing this God earned the right to restore people to a relationship with Him
Colossians 1:22
…yet He has now reconciled you in His fleshly body through death, in order to present you before Him holy and blameless and beyond reproach.
By doing this he solves two problems. First, He completely forgives the sins of all who ask Him.
1 John 1:9
If we confess our sins, He is faithful and righteous to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.
Second, He also gives them the complete righteousness that God expects of them.
2 Corinthians 5:21
He made Him who knew no sin to be sin on our behalf, so that we might become the righteousness of God in Him.
In the eyes of God, it is as if they have never sinned and have lived perfectly “God-Centered” their entire life.
Hebrews 10:14
For by one offering He has perfected for all time those who are sanctified.
Only His work and worth can be the hope of a person. Salvation is completely accomplished by Christ alone, without any assistance from the person.
Response
God will only restore relationship with a person and make them “God-centered” if they turn- away (repent) from their rebellious “self- centeredness” and place their belief on the promise of God to save them through Christ’s work.
Mark 1:15
“The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand; repent and believe in the gospel.”
Romans 10:9
…that if you confess with your mouth Jesus as Lord, and believe in your heart that God raised Him from the dead, you will be saved.
Personally placing trust in God’s promise to save those who ask Him is called … faith
Ephesians 2:8-9
For by grace you have been saved through faith; and that not of yourselves, it is the gift of God; not as a result of works, so that no one may boast.
God will not save a person who is attempting to gain His favor by doing good things or attempting to be “God-centered”
Titus 3:5
He saved us, not on the basis of deeds which we have done in righteousness, but according to His mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewing by the Holy Spirit,
Romans 10:3
For not knowing about God’s righteousness and seeking to establish their own, they did not subject themselves to the righteousness of God.
If a person has true faith in the promise of God to save them, then they will find that they act in a way of increasing obedience to God… since He has truly made them “God-centered”.
I John 2:3
By this we know that we have come to know Him, if we keep His commandments.
James 2:26
For just as the body without the spirit is dead, so also faith without works is dead.
Not only are we brought to spiritual life, but the Spirit of God himself comes into us—dwelling with us to provide help and power to live life for Christ and love supernaturally. The Spirit works within us, confirming in our hearts that we are the Children of God. All who have the Spirit in them are a part of God’s deeply loved family, which He calls the “Church”.
II Corinthians 6:18
“And I will be a father to you, And you shall be sons and daughters to Me,” Says the Lord Almighty.
I Timothy 3:15
but in case I am delayed, I write so that you will know how one ought to conduct himself in the household of God, which is the church of the living God, the pillar and support of the truth.
God loves His Church. Each of His Children are to be deeply connected and functioning in God’s grand family by being a part of a local church. Within God’s family, Christ commissions us to mutually care, serve and share with supernatural love that only He can supply through the Spirit. Through this supernatural love between the members of His family, God is showing the world His presence and the truth of the Gospel of Christ.
Finally, as part of the Church, He then calls of His children into His mission to spread this wonderful news about Himself, which He calls “The gospel” (Matthew 28:18-20). The heart and mission of God become the heart and mission of those who are truly made God’s children by the Cross of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>For Those Who Are Uncertain About the Gospel</title>
   <link href="http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/02/for-those-who-are-uncertain-about-the-gospel/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/02/for-those-who-are-uncertain-about-the-gospel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thank you for taking a few moments to consider the message of the Bible, which it calls “The gospel”. The gospel means “Good News”, but its message is actually some very bad news followed by much better news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you read this introduction, you will probably find yourself in one of the following three categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are aware that you don’t understand the gospel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You may think you have understood the gospel, but actually have not&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or, you may truly understand the gospel and have chosen to reject it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most likely, you belong in one of the first two categories, and the reason is simple. The Bible can be overwhelming and hard to understand. But the message of the Bible doesn’t have to be confusing. God has designed the gospel to be explained in a variety of ways, depending upon audience. Jesus Himself gave the gospel to people in different ways, yet it was always the same message, anchored in the same absolute truths. In this little booklet, we will start at the beginning, and give you a clear explanation of what the Bible &lt;em&gt;says&lt;/em&gt;, and what it &lt;em&gt;means for you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you start through the next few pages, start by asking yourself the five following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does the God of the Bible care most about?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is God’s main problem with mankind?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the concept of salvation… what is God primarily offering mankind?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is Jesus and how does He enable this offer?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does a person receive this offer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can answer these questions, then you are well on your way to finally understanding what the Bible is actually saying… and you are ready to consider what you now want to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>For Those Who are Skeptical About the Gospel</title>
   <link href="http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/02/for-those-who-are-skeptical-about-the-gospel/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/02/for-those-who-are-skeptical-about-the-gospel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We love science, reason and empirical proof. In our western culture we are careful to only trust that which is proven and reasonable. Faith, though acceptable for someone else, is largely seen as a weakness and a crutch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are a person of faith. Some believe in a defined faith such as Judaism, Islam, Buddhism or Christianity, while others, such as secularists, agnostics or atheists, hold to an undefined or more informal belief system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our views on assault, intolerance, bigotry and beauty show that we truly believe in absolutes and ultimate morals. Each of these absolutes go beyond reason and cross over into the realm of faith, regardless of whether we choose to admit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hope of this booklet is to allow you, as a reasonable person who rests on faith (again, all of us do, ultimately), to have the chance to “hear out” a simple summary of the faith that is found in the Bible. Truthfully, our ultimate hope is that in doing so, you hear the voice of Christ calling you and place your faith in Him.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>For Those Who Accept the Gospel</title>
   <link href="http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/02/for-those-who-accept-the-gospel/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://gospelinsix.com/2017/01/02/for-those-who-accept-the-gospel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;God changes people through the gospel. It is the precious foundation for all of our thinking and the most powerful tool we have for accomplishing our mission. We must be gospel-centered people who preach the gospel to ourselves daily and eagerly seek
the opportunities to share it with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gospel is greatly misunderstood and quickly forgotten. One of our greatest obstacles to sharing the gospel is our world’s impression that they already understand it. The same can be said of the Church. Therefore, our greatest ambitions will always be our own personal understanding, our own belief in the gospel and our own ability to convey that message to the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gospel can be explained simply in a few sentences or fully unfolded as the whole 66 books of the Bible. Yet God has given us the freedom and obligation to communicate the gospel in the most effective fashion possible. To accomplish this, our communication
of the gospel needs to meet three standards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It must be Biblically correct and paint a clear story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It must establish core concepts, while clearing up common misconceptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It must provide the believer with clear direction for every area of life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you read through this booklet, consider two things: First, are there areas of your life that suffer from poor understanding, forgetfulness or partial disbelief of the gospel? And secondly, but just as importantly, how would you explain the gospel to the people God has placed in your life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to think through the five questions on the previous page and keep your answers in mind as you work through this booklet.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
